Harry Goodman Collection 075
People's Archive, MLK Library
Harry Goodman Collection
1930-1957
People's Archive, MLK Library
Goodman, Harry
075
2 Linear feet
3 Boxes
Arrangement
Processed without series.
Biographical / Historical
Harry Goodman was born in Brooklyn, New York on June 22, 1912. He attended Alexander Hamilton High School, followed by two years at New York University. At the age of 15, he had his first newspaper job as a reporter for the Brooklyn Citizen. When he was 16, he became a photographer for the Metro News Service in New York. In 1932, Goodman moved to Philadelphia and worked for a weekly pictorial magazine. After the magazine closed in 1933, he relocated to Washington, D.C. and took a job with the Harris and Ewing News Service. The following year, he became an Assistant Manager at the Washington Star, and in 1965, he was promoted to Manager of the Photographic Advertising Department. As a member of the White House Photographers Association, Goodman was present for many official visits from heads-of-state and inauguration ceremonies. In 1977, he retired from the Star, but continued working as a freelance photographer. He also worked for the Keystone News Service, retiring a second time in the mid-1980s. Goodman married his wife, Sara, on March 5, 1934 and they had two sons, Fred and Jeff. He was a founder and choir director of the old Beth Israel Congregation and a member of the Amity Club B'nai Israel Synagogue and Samuel Gombers-Benjamin Franklin Masonic Lodge. Additionally, Goodman taught photography at Southeastern University. He suffered a heart attack, which he survived, in the White House pressroom in 1979. Goodman died of pneumonia at Sibley Memorial Hospital on July 28, 1992.
Custodial History
The collection was donated to the Library in August 2006 by Fred E. Goodman, the son of Harry Goodman.
Related Materials
Collection 061: Washington Star Papers
Scope and Contents
This collection contains undated photographs of floods in the D.C. area; photographs of the King of England's visit to D.C. in 1939; inauguration parade, ball, and ceremony materials from 1953 and 1957; White House News Photographers Association programs from 1947-1957; and a handful of historic editions of the Washington Star.
Photographs; Natural disasters; Kings, queens, rulers, etc; Evening Star Newspaper Co.; Presidents; Inauguration
- Series 1
  - Check Cashing Identification Card - Food Fair Super Market, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Inaugural Ball - Press Pass, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Inaugural Ball - Press Pass, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Inaugural Ball - Program, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Inaugural Ball - Program, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Inaugural Ball - Working Pass, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Inaugural Ceremony - Invitation, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Inaugural Ceremony - Press Pass, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Inaugural Ceremony - Press Pass, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Inaugural Ceremony - Program, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Inaugural Ceremony - Tickets, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Inaugural Parade - Program, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Inaugural Parade - Program, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - War Bond Wallet and Register, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - White House News Photographers Association - Program, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - White House News Photographers Association - Program, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - White House News Photographers Association - Program, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - White House News Photographers Association - Program, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - White House News Photographers Association - Program, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - White House News Photographers Association - Program, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - White House News Photographers Association - Tickets, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Photograph - Queen Elizabeth at Mt. Vernon, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photograph - King George and President Roosevelt, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Photograph - King George - Washington DC, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Photograph - King George - Boarding Ship - Washington DC, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Photograph - King George and President Roosevelt at Washington's Tomb - Mt. Vernon, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photograph - Queen Elizabeth and Mrs. Roosevelt, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photograph - King George and Queen in Washington DC, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Photograph - King George and Mrs. Roosevelt at Mt. Vernon, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Photograph - King George and President Roosevelt, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Photograph - King George of England at Mt. Vernon, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Photograph - King George - Washington DC, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Photograph - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Flood - Washington DC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Star Issues, October 29 1930, April 13 1949, December 16 1952 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 2 copies of "The Washington Star's First 100 Years", Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)